A Finding Aid to the Jack Stewart Papers, 1926-2010, in the Archives of American Art AAA.stewjack
Archives of American Art
- Research Files on Graffiti, 1972-2010; Series 4; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 5-7,11
  - Interviews with Graffiti Writers (Box 6)
    - "Tracy, Chi-Chi, Cliff, Zest, Clyde Pel in Studio", 1974 April 19; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Chi-Chi and Tracy in my studio", 1974 July 1; 1 Sound cassettes; 1 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "Tracy and Chi-Chi", 1974; 1 Sound cassettes label reads "Transfer from large reel???" (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Tracy, Chi-Chi, Cliff, Zest, and Clyde in Studio", 1974; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Wanted Clubhouse, Woodyrest Ave.", 1974 May 11; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "T-168 with Bill Clark, winter of 1974", 1 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Tracy and Chi-Chi", 1976 April 17; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "EHP and Letters Riso", 1976 September 29; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Graffiti; JS, X Vandils (sic) [illegible], Gary, Hispanic Savage Ones Brooklyn", 1980-1989; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Caine, Johnny, Wasp", 1981 November 4; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "T-168, Billy 167, Wasp I, Daze in Studio, parts I and II", 1981 November 15; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "12 Lee, Pink, Craine, Haze, parts 1 and 2", 1981 November 16; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Meeting with Chris who writes Freedo, Coco 144, Stan", 1982 October 12; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Meeting with Chris (Freedom)", 1982 November 2; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Wasp, Daze, Pink", 1982 November 8; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Tracy and Billy review book" parts 1 and 2, 1983 February 15; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "T-168, Wasp, Mitch", 1983 September 5; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Taki '83", 1983 September 9; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Delores Blade (wife) and Sean, parts 1 and 2", 1983 December 5; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Blade", 1984 March 3; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Bama (Amrl) and Wicked Gary (WG)", 1984 November 14; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Bama and Michael", 1985 January 11; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Tracy and Chi-Chi", 1985 January 15; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lectures, 1979-2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Maps, New York City Subway, circa 1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Museum of the City of New York Graffiti Collection, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Names/Tags of Graffiti Writers, "Tracy 6 - Hell" and Names on Lavatory Door at Stewart's Studio, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Names/Tags of Graffiti Writers, Lists, 1985 March 10-April 19 (Box 7, Folder 11-20)
  - New York City Police Department, "Profile of a Common Offender,", circa 1976 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - New York City Transit Authority, undated; 1960s-1980s (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Periodicals, undated, 1990s-2000s (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Signatures of Graffiti Writers (photocopy), undated; 1970s-2000s; Oversized material housed in Box 11 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Slide Lists, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Slides Loaned, 1981-2001 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Oversized Signatures of Graffiti Writers from Box 7 Folder 25, circa 1972-1975 (Box 11)
- Printed Material, circa 1945-2002; Series 5; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 8, 11, OV 13
  The miscellaneous items are the catalog of a silent auction and lecture announcements. Posters are for events sponsored by Cooper Union's Art Department and exhibitions. The Ocean Grove Memorial Day Weekend Art Event was an annual affair organized by Stewart for more than a decade.
  Additional printed material is included among biographical materials (Series 1), writings and notes (Series 3), research files on graffiti (Series 4), and scrapbooks (Series 6).
  - Book of House Plans illustrated by Stewart, circa 1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (undated, 1930s-2000s) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1950s-2000s; Oversized Clippings housed in Box 11 (Box 8, Folder 3-8)
  - Exhibition Advertisements, 1964-1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, undated; 1950s-2000s (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960s-2005 (Box 8, Folder 11-18)
  - Miscellaneous Items, undated; 1980s-2002 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters, 1980s-2005 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Ocean Grove Memorial Day Event, 1980s-1990s; undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Posters, 1971-1973; undated; Oversized Posters from Box 8, Folder 22 housed in OV 13 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Press Releases, 1950s-2000s (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - Design and Plans, undated 1953-1979; Oversized Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - Designs and Plans housed in Box 11 and OV 13 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - Drawings, Miscellaneous Subjects, undated; (1970s-2000) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart - School Catalogs and Advertisements, 1950s-1970s; undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Oversized Printed Material, Clippings from Box 8, Folder 4, 1953-1968 (Box 11)
  - Oversized Printed Material, Posters from Box 8, Folder 22, 1974 (Box OV12, Box OV 12)
  - Oversized Printed Material, Reproductions of Artwork by Stewart from Box 8, Folder 24, 1962-1978 (Box )V 13, Box 11)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1990-2003; Series 6; 0.2 Linear feet Box 8
  This series consists of two scrapbooks, both containing mixed materials. "Anatomy of a Commissioned Work" includes articles and notes about brain function, a price list for 1990 exhibition of Anodyne: The Brain Painting at The Broome Street Galley, and excerpts from Stewart's correspondence with Rodman Townsend that were included in the exhibition.
  - "Anatomy of a Commissioned Work: Anodyne: The Brain Painting,", circa 1990-2003 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Jack Stewart Exhibition of Paintings and Drawings," The Broome Street Galley, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Artwork, 1946-2000; Series 7; 0.3 Linear feet Boxes 8, 11, OV 12
  This series consists of designs and plans, drawings, paintings, and an etching by Jack Stewart.
  - Designs and Plans - Murals, undated; 1954-1990s (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Designs and Plans - Student Work, Columbia University, circa 1951-circa 1953; Oversized Artwork - Student Work housed in Box 11 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Designs and Plans - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops, 1953-1958; undated; Oversized Designs and Plans - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops housed in Box 11, OV 12 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Designs and Plans - Terre Haute Plan and Unidentified Projects, undated; 1979 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Drawings, 1946-2000; undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Etching, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Paintings, 1953-2003; undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Oversized Designs and Plans - Student Work from Box 8 Folder 30, circa 1951-circa 1953 (Box 11)
  - Oversized Designs, Plans and Drawings - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops from Box 8, Folder 31, undated (Box OV 12, Box 11)
  - Oversized Designs and Plans - Tables and Mosaic Table Tops from Box 8 Folder 31, undated; 1953-1958 (Box OV 12)
- Sketchbooks, 1951-2004; Series 8; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
  Sketchbooks (44 volumes) contain drawings and sketches in pencil and ink. Among the subjects are: travel sketches from Hong Kong, China, and Greece; heads and a portrait of Stewart's mother; 10th Annual Ocean Grove Memorial Day Art Event; and many studies of sheep made for the Cluett Mural commission. Two volumes include writings. Of particular interest are notes on Franz Kline's funeral, May 1962.
  Although numbered in several overlapping sequences, the sketchbooks are arranged chronologically. Additional sketches of Guilin, China are found among the artwork (Series 7).
  - Volume 1: "M-29", undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Volume 2: "Sketches and 1 Poem ('Shells and Stones') 1951" (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Volume 3: "Sketches 1957 J.S. L-2" (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Volume 4: "Notes on Kline's funeral May 1962, Visit to Roman Bronze Art Foundry, Sketches of Polo Ponies at 92nd Street Armory Polo Games 1960. M-2", 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Volune 5: "1962 M-3" with Sketches of Greece and Items in the Archaeological Museum Istanbul (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Volume 6: "Sketches 1963 J.S. L-3" (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Volume 7: Travel Sketches, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Volume 8: "Guilin, China 1987 L-5" (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Volume 9: "1987 Sketches. Hong Kong and Guilin, China Sept. 1987 M-G J.S. [illegible] #20 was done on the train to Albany looking out the widow at the Hudson River. Dwgs. 21-24 were done in Ocean Grove J.S." (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Volume 10: "Book M-5 1st studies for Cluett mural. Sketch of O.G. [Ocean Grove] fishing pier. Dark sketches of trees. Sketch of Dover Cliffs", circa 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Volume11: "M-3 All Sheep J.S. 13 drawings of sheep at NYC Central Park Children's Zoo. Studies for Cluett Peaabody mural", 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Volume 12: "Sheep Drawings '89 L-6 5 sheep heads", 1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Volume 13: "10th Annual Ocean Grove Memorial Day Art Event L-14", circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Volume 14: "[illegible] sketch. Sketches for paintings using concave mirrors. Potala Palace. Notes on my development. 1991 M-10" (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Volume 15: "6-92 Brain Circus studies of mammals at Nat. Hist. Mus. - 5 old men under Big Tree M-11", 1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Volume 16: "M-19 '92-'97", 1992-1997 (Box 9, Folder 8, Folder 9)
  - Volume 17: "L-9 Circus [illegible] Aug. 1993" (Box 9, Folder 9, Folder 10)
  - Volume 18: "1994 M-13 contains MH #147 unfinished" (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Volume 19: "L-10 1994-1995" (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Volume 20: "O.G. [Ocean Grove] and aerial views on trip to Atl. Book #0, 1994-1995" (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Volume 21: "1995 Brooklyn Bot. Gardens. Marina in horse show. M-14" (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Volume 22: "M-27", 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Volume 23: "#2 1996" (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Volume 24: "1996 M-16" (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Volume 25: "Heads, O.G. [Ocean Grove], Lauren, 1996 Aug., 16 heads, Book #1" (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Volume 26: "1996; Subway Station, Surf at O.G. [Ocean Grove], Heads; 1997: Heads [illegible] Clouds in Atlanta, Book #3", 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Volume 27: "96 3 heads", 2001; 1996 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Volume 28: "Portrait of Mother, M-18 1996-1997" (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Volume 29: "#5 '96 6 heads", 1996-2000 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Volume: 30 "1/27/97 McMurtry, Ossana at 97th St. Y; Atlanta 2/16/97, Ma's back of head, wink-incomplete Jan. and Feb.1997 #8" (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Volume 31: "M-17 7-13-97 1:30 p.m. NY-Cincinnati, Cin-Atlanta arr. 5:30 p.m.", 1997 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Volume 32: "ATL 10/17 to 10/27/97, NYC: Met Opera, Barber Seville, Pushka and Remmy #6", 1997 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Volume 33: "2 heads, #9", 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Volume 34: "Basto 7/18/97, Belmont 5/16/98, Studies for BMT Proposal 5/00, M-20", 1997-2000 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Volume 35: "April-May 1998, #10", 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Volume 36: "98 and 2K, Book #17", 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Volume 37: "#12", 1999 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Volume 38: "10 heads, #13", 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Volume 39: "#14", 2000 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Volume 40: "#15", 2000 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Volume 41: "#16", 2000 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Volume 42: "#17", 2000 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Volume 43: "Book #21", 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Volume 44:"Book #22", 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1950s-2010; Series 9; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 10-11
  Photographs, digital images, and 35-mm color slides are of Stewart and other individuals, his artwork, and miscellaneous subjects. The exhibition openings and installations documented are: Grippi-Waddell Gallery (1964); Blue Hill Cultural Center, Pearl River, NY (1986); and "Anodyne: The Brain Painting" at The Broome Street Gallery (1990) and New York Hall of Science (2003); and a retrospective exhibition at the Ogden Museum of Southern Art.
  Additional photographic materials are included among biographical materials (Series 1), writings and notes (Series 3), research files on graffiti (Series 4), and scrapbooks (Series 6).
  - At 9th Annual Memorial Day Art Event, Ocean Grove, NJ, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Jack Stewart at Work and with his Paintings and Murals, undated; circa 1950s-1990s; Oversized material housed in Box 11 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jack Stewart in Urbino, Italy, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jack Stewart with Others, 1970s-1990s; undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Artwork by Stewart - Mosaic Tables, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Artwork by Stewart - Murals, undated; 1950s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Artwork by Stewart - Paintings, undated; 1950s-2010; Includes 1 CD (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Openings and Installations, 1960s-2010; undated; Includes 1 CD and 4 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects - Architect's Rendering of a Hotel; Tree, circa 1960s; 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects - World Trade Center Devastation, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)